weatherford.com 2019-08-08

# Privacy Policy | Weatherford International

Weatherford International plc (“ **Weatherford” or “We** ”) is committed to protecting the privacy of your information and personal data collected during your visit to this Site.  In this Site Privacy Policy (“ **Policy** ”), Weatherford provides information about how We collect, use and transfer personal data from you, a Site visitor, through www.weatherford.com, other Sites that We operate and Weatherford proprietary software that we host ourselves or through a third-party hosting provider where there is a  link to this Policy (collectively, for the purposes of this Policy, the “ **Site** ”).

SCOPE

This Policy covers only personal data collected through the Site and not any other data collection or processing, including, without limitation, data collection practices of other web pages to which We link or data that We or our affiliates collect offline or through sites that do not display a direct link to this Policy. Occasionally, We may refer to this Policy in notices and consent requests related to surveys and special-purpose web pages; under such circumstances, this Policy applies as modified in the particular notice or consent request (e.g., with respect to types of data collected or purposes of collection). Some of our business units and web pages apply this Policy subject to specifically disclosed modifications, supplements or exceptions.

ACCEPTANCE

PLEASE READ THIS POLICY CAREFULLY TO UNDERSTAND OUR POLICIES AND PRACTICES REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND HOW WE WILL TREAT IT.  IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR POLICIES AND PRACTICES, YOUR CHOICE IS NOT TO USE OUR SITE. BY ACCESSING OR USING THE SITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS POLICY. THIS POLICY MAY CHANGE FROM TIME TO TIME.

**TO THE FULLEST EXTENT ALLOWED BY APPLICABLE LAW, YOU HEREBY IRREVOCABLY AGREE BY VIRTUE OF USING THE SITE TO ANY AND ALL PERSONAL DATA COLLECTION BY THE SITE AS EXPRESSLY DESCRIBED IN THIS POLICY OR AS OTHERWISE CONTEMPLATED HEREIN.  FURTHERMORE, TO THE FULLEST EXTENT ALLOWED BY APPLICABLE LAW, YOU ALSO HEREBY IRREVOCABLY AGREE THAT SUCH PERSONAL DATA COLLECTION MAY RESULT IN PROCESSING AND/OR TRANSFERRING YOUR PERSONAL DATA TO WEATHERFORD’S SUBSIDIARIES AND AFFILIATES OR THIRD PARTIES IN COUNTRIES WHICH MIGHT NOT HAVE THE SAME LEVEL OF DATA PROTECTION LIKE IN YOUR HOME COUNTRY.**

TYPES OF PERSONAL DATA AND COLLECTION METHODS

Through the Site, We receive personal data that you actively submit as well as data that We track:

**Actively Submitted Personal Data:** When you request information, respond to an online survey or otherwise actively send us personal data, or access software We or one of our third-party hosting partners host, We usually collect personal data such as your name, email address, mailing address, telephone number(s), log-on credentials, and certain information related to the business you represent. In each such instance, you will know what personal data We collect through the Site, because you actively submit it.

**Passively Tracked Data:** When you visit the Site, We also passively track information on your computer and Internet connection, such as the IP address of your computer and/or Internet service provider, the date and time you access our Sites, the Internet address of Sites from which you link to our Site, the computer technology you are using and your movements and preferences on the Site. use technology that many other websites and applications employ, including, without limitation, web beacons, “cookies” (flash or browser based) or small data files stored on your computer’s hard drive, to collect information such as the aforementioned. In some instances, We also use cookies to collect information in connection with future visits from the Site, to recognize you as a previous visitor and to track your activity on the Site. You can refuse cookies by turning them off on your browser. Weatherford currently does not respond to Do Not Track signals. For more information on the cookies collected by Weatherford, please see Weatherford’s Cookie Policy.

**Combinations:** Unless you also actively submit personal data such as your name or address, passively tracked data does not typically allow us to identify you personally (even though it can theoretically be done, We do not have the means or an interest to find out who you are, unless you identify yourself voluntarily through an active submission of data). To the extent permitted by applicable law, We reserve the right to combine passively tracked data with personal data that you actively submit.

COLLECTION PURPOSES AND LEGAL BASIS, USE OF DATA

We collect passively tracked personal data primarily for purposes of administering, protecting and improving the Site and our systems, to better understand the preferences of Site visitors, to identify server problems, to compile aggregated statistics about Site usage, and to help personalize your experience of our Site.

We collect actively submitted personal data primarily for two purposes: Firstly, for the purpose for which you originally sent us the personal data (e.g., to mail information to you). Two, for purposes of informing you about products and services; you can opt out of receiving marketing emails as explained below.

Our use of your personal data will always have a lawful basis, either because it is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data (e.g. by subscribing to emails or blogs), or because it is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your fundamental rights and freedoms taking into consideration your reasonable expectations after reading this Policy.

DISCLOSURES OF PERSONAL DATA

We do not sell or rent your information to telemarketers and do not share your personal data with others, except as follows: We freely share your information with our affiliates. We also share your personal data with agents and service providers who use the data only on our behalf and for our purposes under confidentiality agreements. We may share your personal data as required by law or in the interest of protecting or exercising our or others’ legal rights, e.g., without limitation, in connection with requests from law enforcement officials and in connection with court proceedings. We may share or transfer your personal data in connection with a prospective or actual sale, merger, transfer or other reorganization of all or parts of our business. Also, We reserve the right to fully use and disclose any information collected via the Site that is not in personally identifiable form.

OPT-OUT

In connection with promotions or other projects, We may ask you specifically whether you have objections against a certain kind of personal data use or sharing. If you opt-out under such circumstances, We will respect your decision. To opt-out of receiving further commercial emails or to unsubscribe from services, please click the unsubscribe link contained in the commercial email or contact us. Please note that other data recipients have their own data privacy policies, which may differ from ours and you would have to contact them separately with respect to opt-out requests.

RIGHTS

As a Site user, you have the following rights under the applicable data protection laws:

  * The right to be informed about our collection and use of personal data;
  * The right of access to the personal data We hold about you;
  * The right to rectification if any personal data We hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * The right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask us to delete any personal data We hold about you;
  * The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;
  * The right to data portability (obtaining a copy of your personal data to re-use with another service or organization);
  * The right to object to us using your personal data for particular purposes; and
  * Rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.

If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, please contact us using the details provided below and We will do our best to solve the problem for you. If We are unable to help, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority.

SECURITY

Transmissions over the Internet are never 100% secure or error-free. However, We take reasonable steps to protect your personal data from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. It is your responsibility to safeguard any information you use to access the Site and to notify us if you ever suspect that such information has been compromised. You are solely responsible for any unauthorized use of the Site.

STORING

All personal data is processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. 

Some or all of your personal data may be stored outside of the European Economic Area (“the EEA”). (The EEA consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein.) You are deemed to accept and agree to this by using our Site and submitting personal data to us. If We do store data outside the EEA, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal data is treated as safely and securely as it would be within the EEA and under the applicable data protection laws including the conclusion of the Standard Contractual Clauses, Privacy Shield, etc.

SPECIAL NOTICE – CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

We do not intentionally or knowingly collect personal data from children under the age of 13 and We request that individuals under the age of 13 not submit any personal information on the Site.

AMENDMENTS

We reserve the right to change this Policy from time to time and in our sole discretion. We reserve the right to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Policy at any time, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the Policy the date it was last updated. When you visit the Site, you are accepting the current version of this Policy as posted on or linked to the Site at that time.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on April 9, 2019.

CONTACT US

Should you wish to exercise your opt-out or any other rights you may have by law, or have questions about this Policy, please email us at [privacy@weatherford.com](mailto:privacy@weatherford.com) or write us at Weatherford, 2000 St. James Place Houston Texas 77056 Attn: Data Protection Officer.
